Guide to the Diane Scrima Collection of Recipe Booklets and Cookbooks, 1936-1983.
Scrima, Diane Collection of Recipe Booklets and Cookbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Diane Scrima Collection of Recipe Booklets and Cookbooks, 1936-1983.
8568
Scrima, Diane J.
.6 cubic foot.
Publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection primarily consists of recipe pamphlets and cookbooks produced by General Foods, with a few by other corporations.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Diane Scrima worked for General Foods Corporation for 26 years.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection primarily consists of recipe pamphlets and cookbooks produced by General Foods, with a few by other corporations.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Scrima, Diane J.; General Foods Corporation.
Subjects:
Cooking.; Cooking, American.; Formulas, recipes, etc.
Form and Genre Terms:
Recipes.; Cookbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Related material in collection #8006, Food and recipe booklets collection.
SERIES LIST
Series I. By General Foods
Box 1
Series II. By Other Corporations
Box 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. By General Foods
  - Around-The-World Desserts, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baker's Chocolate and Coconut Favorites, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clock-watcher's cookbook, for busy days - quick, simple meals from Minute Rice, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Contemporary Cook's Diary, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Good Looking Desserts, A Cooking with Jell-O, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Joys of Jell-O, Gelatin Dessert, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Jam and Jelly Making: A Pleasurable Art, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jet set meals with a foreign accent, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Recipe Sampler from Log Cabin, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pancake Parties Plus (Log Cabin), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Finishing Touch, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Sanka Spirit, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Setpoint Diet, the Food and Exercise Connection for Lasting Weight Control, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Well-Dressed Dessert, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The whys of weight… and what to do about it, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Wake up to tang… and new ways to enjoy it!, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - With A Pinch of Love, Cecile Bexton, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baker’s Famous Chocolate Recipes, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The home meal planner… a key to better meals, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Maxwell House Coffee Cookbook, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Proof of the Pudding, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Timeless Recipes with Minute Rice, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Baker’s famous chocolate frostings made easy…, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Flavor Sparkling Recipes with Tang, includes letter form GF President and coupon, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Jell-O Pudding Idea Book, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - In the Best Taste - Flair Without Fuss With Shake’n Bake, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Drinks for a lively day, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Say Pudding Please, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Be a Coconutty Cook with Baker’s Coconut Crunchies, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Proof of the Pudding, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Barbecues for All Seasons, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Magical Desserts with Whip’n Chill Deluxe Dessert Mix, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cut-Ups - Celebration Cakes by Baker’s Coconut, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Once upon a table - Meals to Please a Man, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Food For You and Your Family, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - The Wonderland of Homemade Jams and Jellies, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The New Joys of Jell-O, Gelatin Dessert, 2nd edition, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Jell-O Pudding Sampler, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Birds Eye, New Super Suppers, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Birds Eye Super Soups - 5 minutes from simmer to serve, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Coffee Makes It Delicious - The Coffee Cookbook from Maxwell House Coffee, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Baker’s Book of Chocolate Riches, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Sanka, Good Beginnings - Recipes, Exercises, Ideas for Living Well Year Round, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series II. By Other Corporations
  - Chambers Corp., How to cook with the gass turned off, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Channing L. Bete Co., Inc., a-b-c's of good nutrition, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Culinary Arts Institute, 500 Tasty Snacks - ideas for entertaining, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Culinary Arts Institute, The Cookie Book, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Culinary Arts Institute, The Cheese Cookbook, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Culinary Arts Institute, The Southern and Southwestern Cookbook, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Culinary Arts Institute, Quick Dishes for the Woman in a Hurray, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ekco Housewares Co, Tempting Recipes for Cakes, Pies, Breads - 30 recipes you’ll use from brunch ’til TV snack time., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General Wine and Spirits Co., The Cordial Touch - A Guide to Creative Cooking From Leroux, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Good Food, first issue, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Good Housekeeping, Book of Cookies - to gladden the hearts of cookie-lovers, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hennessy Cognac, Gourmet’s Guide to Cognac, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - McKesson Liquor Co., Discover Gold - Recipes for making delicious drinks with Liquore Galliano, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - McKesson Liquor Co., …and add a measure of gold, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Meredith Corp., Shortcut Cooking, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, Metropolitan Cook Book, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ocean Spray Cranberries, Inc., Mix around with Cranberry Juice, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pan-American Coffee Bureau, More Fun With Coffee, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pillsbury, Fun-Filled Butter Cookie Cookbook, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pillsbury, Fruits and Vegetables Cookbook, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Quaker Oats Company, Stretching Food Dollars - Meal planning hints and budget-wise recipes, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Quaker Oats Company, The Quaker Cookie Jar, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Quaker Oats Company, Those Picture Pretties, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Round the World Books Inc., A Permanent Collection of the World’s Best Recipes: Cakes, Pies, and Pastries, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Spice Islands Company, Enticing Seafood, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spice Islands Company, Intriguing Poultry Dishes, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spice Islands Company, Recipes for Beef Stock Base, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spice Islands Company, Recipes for Instant Toasted Onions, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spice Islands Company, Succulent Meat Dishes, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spice Islands Company, “Waistline Watcher” Vegetable Recipes, featuring Instant Toasted Onions, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spice Islands Company, The Story and Uses of Spice Islands Exclusive Coffee and Teas, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)